<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Farmer</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/</link><description>Recent content on Farmer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:36:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AKS Cluster</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/aks-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 19:30:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/aks-cluster/</guid><description>Overview The AKS Cluster builder is used to create AKS clusters.
Container Service (Microsoft.ContainerService/managedClusters) AKS Builder Keywords The AKS Builder constructs AKS clusters.
Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the AKS cluster. dns_prefix Sets the DNS prefix of the AKS cluster. enable_rbac Enable Kubernetes Role-Based Access Control. add_agent_pools Adds agent pools to the AKS cluster.</description></item><item><title>Generating templates</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/template-generation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:13:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/template-generation/</guid><description>Farmer supports several ways to &amp;ldquo;output&amp;rdquo; ARM templates.
Generating JSON as a string You can generate an ARM template as a plain string:
let json = deployment.Template |&amp;gt; Writer.toJson // prints out the JSON printfn &amp;#34;%s&amp;#34; json Writing to a file You can write out the ARM template directly to a file, from which you can then deploy to Azure using whichever mechanism you already use e.g. Azure CLI, Powershell, REST API etc.</description></item><item><title>App Insights</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/app-insights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/app-insights/</guid><description>Overview The App Insights builder is used to create Application Insights accounts. Use this if you need a standalone AI instance; if you need one for a web app, the web app will create one by default and configure the application settings automatically.
Application Insights (Microsoft.Insights/components) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the App Insights instance. disable_ip_masking Disable IP masking.</description></item><item><title>ARM Deployment</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/arm/</guid><description>Overview The ARM deployment builder is always the top-level element of your deployment. It contains the manifest of all Farmer resources that you create.
Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose location Sets the default location of all resources. add_resource Adds a resource to the template. add_resources Adds a collection of resources to the template. output Creates an output value that will be returned by the ARM template.</description></item><item><title>Your first Farmer template</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/quickstart-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:41:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/quickstart-1/</guid><description>Introduction In this exercise, you&amp;rsquo;ll:
create a web application with a fully-configured Application Insights instance create an ARM deployment object and assign the web app to it generate an ARM template Creating a Farmer app Create an F# console application using the .NET SDK and add the Farmer package in an empty directory:
dotnet new console -lang F# dotnet add package Farmer Farmer also has a .NET template to get started even more quickly!</description></item><item><title>1. The Farmer Pipeline</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/1-the-farmer-pipline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/1-the-farmer-pipline/</guid><description>This step will get you up and running by incorporate something quickly and easily into the Farmer pipeline that emits a valid Azure Container Registry.
Step 1.1: Prototype and test using an fsx file Technically this step is not necessary but it is the quickest way to get a working deployment from which you can iterate upon.
Start by looking at this sample and identifying the section of JSON that relates to the resource we want - in our case, the Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>ARM Basics</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/arm-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/arm-basics/</guid><description>Skip this section if you are already familiar with ARM Templates
This won&amp;rsquo;t be an introduction to Azure Resource Manager or ARM templates. Instead let&amp;rsquo;s go through the main parts that are important for creating a new resource.
The main parts of ARM Templates can be broken into resources, outputs, variables, and parameters. Farmer has limited support for parameters and no support for variables, so we will not cover them.</description></item><item><title>Bing Search</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/bing-search/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 07:33:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/bing-search/</guid><description>Overview The Bing Search builder is used to create Azure Bing Search instances.
Bing Search (Microsoft.Bing/accounts, kind: Bing.Search.v7) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Bing Search instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to F1 (free). statistics Sets the statisticsEnabled property of the instance. Defaults to false Configuration Members Member Purpose Key Gets the ARM expression path to the Key of this Bing Search instance.</description></item><item><title>Bastion Host</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/bastion-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/bastion-host/</guid><description>Overview The Bastion Host builder creates a bastion host to access resources inside a virtual network. It also creates a static public IP for the bastion host.
BastionHosts (Microsoft.Network/bastionHosts) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose BastionHost vnet Name of the virtual network the bastion host can access Example #r @&amp;#34;./libs/Newtonsoft.Json.dll&amp;#34; #r @&amp;#34;../../src/Farmer/bin/Debug/netstandard2.0/Farmer.dll&amp;#34; open Farmer open Farmer.Builders arm { location Location.</description></item><item><title>Outputs and ARM Expressions</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/outputs-and-expressions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:50:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/outputs-and-expressions/</guid><description>Outputs can be created in Farmer for any ARM Expression, Resource Name or any optional string. ARM Expressions are most useful in this case for referring to values that only exist at deployment time, such as connection strings.
Creating ARM Expressions Farmer ARM expressions are in reality just wrapped strings, and are easy to create. For example, the code to create a Storage Key property is similar to this:</description></item><item><title>ARM Expressions</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/expressions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:13:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/expressions/</guid><description>ARM template expressions are a way of safely storing string values which contain expressions that are evaluated at deployment time by the Azure. ARM expressions can also contain a set of predefined functions supported by the ARM runtime. They can be passed back as outputs and used further downstream
Farmer understands how to use ARM expressions and provides functionality to correctly wrap and unwrap them as raw strings into a JSON template.</description></item><item><title>Parameters and Variables</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/parameters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:13:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/parameters/</guid><description>ARM templates support the idea both of parameterisation of templates and of the use of variables within a template for e.g. placeholders and re-using values.
Farmer, by design, has only limited support for parameters and no support for variables. We don&amp;rsquo;t plan on adding rich support for either of these for the following reasons:
We want to keep the Farmer codebase simple for maintainers We want to keep the Farmer API simple for users We want to keep the generated ARM templates as readable as possible We feel that instead of trying to embed conditional logic and program flow directly inside ARM templates in JSON, if you wish to parameterise your template that you should use a real programming language to do that: in this case, F#.</description></item><item><title>Working with multiple resources</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/quickstart-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:41:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/quickstart-2/</guid><description>Introduction In this quickstart, you&amp;rsquo;ll expand on the deployment authored in the previous quickstart as follows:
add an Azure storage account add an application setting to the web app that references the storage account&amp;rsquo;s key set a dependency between the two resources Creating a storage account Create a storage account by using the storageAccount builder.
let myStorage = storageAccount { name &amp;#34;yourfirststorage&amp;#34; } Azure Storage Account names must be globally unique and between 3-24 alphanumeric lower-case characters!</description></item><item><title>2. The IArmResource</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/2-iarm-resource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/2-iarm-resource/</guid><description>In this exercise, we&amp;rsquo;ll migrate our code from the previous step directly into the Farmer codebase.
Step 2.1: Migrating to IArmResource Now that you know that your resource model produces the correct Json value when passed into Farmer, we can now create a proper type that contains the &amp;ldquo;parameterised&amp;rdquo; parts of the above function, such as name, sku and adminUserEnabled, and properly takes part in the Farmer pipeline, by implementing the IArmResource interface.</description></item><item><title>Dependencies</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/dependencies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 09:13:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/dependencies/</guid><description>ARM resources can depend on one another, and Farmer caters for this as well. Dependencies guarantee that when resources are created, Azure will provision them in the correct order so that e.g. a storage account is created before Azure tries to grab the storage account key / connection string for your web app setting.
Much of this work is done for you:
Farmer creates multiple resources for you at the builder level, and will ensure that the appropriate dependencies are set for you - for example, when creating a SQL Azure instance, Farmer will automatically ensure that the database depends on the server.</description></item><item><title>Outputs</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/outputs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 09:13:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/outputs/</guid><description>ARM templates also support the notion of outputs. Outputs can be used to provide your Farmer applications with values which were generated during the deployment process, to be used further downstream.
For example, you may wish to prime an Azure storage account with data post-creation. In this case, one way is to return back out the connection string of the storage account and use that to connect and upload your data.</description></item><item><title>Container Group</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 19:30:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-group/</guid><description>Overview The Container Group builder is used to create Azure Container Group instances.
Container Group (Microsoft.ContainerInstance/containerGroups) Network Profile (Microsoft.Network/networkProfiles) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose containerInstance name Sets the name of the container instance. containerInstance image Sets the container image. containerInstance command Sets the commands to execute within the container instance in exec form. containerInstance add_ports Sets the ports the container exposes.</description></item><item><title>Container Registry</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-registry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 19:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-registry/</guid><description>Overview The Container Registry builder is used to create Azure Container Registry (ACR) instances.
Container Registry (Microsoft.ContainerRegistry/registries) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Container Registry instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to Basic. enable_admin_user The value that indicates whether the admin user is enabled. Configuration Members Member Purpose Password Gets the ARM expression path to the first admin password of this container registry if admin user was enabled.</description></item><item><title>Cognitive Services</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cognitive-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cognitive-services/</guid><description>Overview The Cognitive Services builder is used to create Azure Cognitive Services instances.
Cognitive Services (Microsoft.CognitiveServices/accounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Cognitive Services instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to F0 (free). api Specifies the Kind of api to use for the service instance. Defaults to AllInOne. Configuration Members Member Purpose Key Gets the ARM expression path to the Key of this Cognitive Services instance.</description></item><item><title>Cosmos DB</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cosmos-db/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cosmos-db/</guid><description>Overview The CosmosDb package containers two builders, used to create databases and containers.
CosmosDB Account (Microsoft.DocumentDb/databaseAccounts) CosmosDB SQL (Microsoft.DocumentDB/databaseAccounts/sqlDatabases) CosmosDB MongoDB (Microsoft.DocumentDB/databaseAccounts/mongodbDatabases) CosmosDB SQL Container (Microsoft.DocumentDb/databaseAccounts/sqlDatabases/containers) There is currently only support for document databases (the so-called &amp;ldquo;SQL API&amp;rdquo;), with support for Gremlin, Table and Cassandra data models planned.
Cosmos DB Builder The CosmosDB builder abstracts the idea of account and database into one. If you wish to &amp;ldquo;re-use&amp;rdquo; an already-created Cosmos DB account, use link_to_account keyword - no account will be created and the database will be attached to the existing one.</description></item><item><title>Deploying to Azure</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/quickstart-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:41:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/quickstart-3/</guid><description>Introduction In this exercise, you&amp;rsquo;ll update the application to deploy the generated ARM template to Azure directly from Farmer.
Farmer generates normal ARM templates. You use all of the standard mechanisms for deploying ARM templates such as through the portal, Powershell, .NET or Azure CLI etc. This tutorial shows you a simple way to deploy templates from your development machine directly from within F#.
Install the Azure CLI If you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so already, install the Azure CLI on your machine.</description></item><item><title>3. The IBuilder interface</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/3-ibuilder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/3-ibuilder/</guid><description>Sometimes, ARM resources are captured at a level of abstraction that is too low for us to reason about. In such cases, we may wish to use the IBuilder interface. An IBuilder is not only even easier to consume by users than the F# record we looked at in the previous exercise, but can create multiple IArmResource objects at once. This is especially useful for more complex resources that tend to come in groups of two or three together - for example, Server Farm and Web Apps, or Cosmos DB Accounts, Databases and Containers.</description></item><item><title>CDN</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cdn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cdn/</guid><description>Overview The CDN builder is used to create Azure Content Delivery Network instances.
CDN Profile (Microsoft.Cdn/profiles) CDN Endpoint (Microsoft.Cdn/profiles/endpoints) CDN Custom Domain (Microsoft.Cdn/profiles/endpoints/customDomains) There are two builders available:
The CDN builder, which maps to a CDN profile. The Endpoint builder, which creates endpoints and custom domains. Endpoints are created within a CDN. CDN Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the CDN instance.</description></item><item><title>Databricks Workspace</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/databricks-workspace/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/databricks-workspace/</guid><description>Overview The Databricks Workspace builder is used to create Azure Databricks Workspaces.
Workspace (Microsoft.Databricks/workspaces) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the workspace. sku Sets the pricing tier of the workspace. Defaults to Standard Tier. encrypt_with_key_vault Given a key vault builder / resourceid / vault name, and the name of a key, activates the use of Key Vault for the key store.</description></item><item><title>Deployment Script</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/deployment-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 15:19:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/deployment-script/</guid><description>Overview The Deployment Script builder is used to execute Azure CLI scripts as part of an ARM deployment.
Deployment Script (Microsoft.Resources/deploymentScripts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the deployment script resource. arguments List of arguments to pass to the script. cleanup_on_success The script will only be cleaned up on success to allow for inspection of failures.</description></item><item><title>DNS Zone</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 18:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/dns/</guid><description>Overview The DNS Zone module contains two types of builders - dnsZone, used to create DNS Zones, and ___Record (like cnameRecord, aRecord, ..), used to create DNS Records sets. It supports most record types (except SOA, SRV and CAA) and has specific builders for every record type.
DNS Zone (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones) A Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/A) AAAA Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/AAAA) CNAME Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/CNAME) TXT Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/TXT) MX Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/MX) NS Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/NS) PTR Record (Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Data Lake</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/data-lake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:55:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/data-lake/</guid><description>Overview The Data Lake builder is used to create Azure Data Lake instances.
Data Lake (Microsoft.DataLakeStore/accounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Cognitive Services instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to Consumption. enable_encryption Turns on data lake encryption. Example open Farmer open Farmer.Builders let myLake = dataLake { name &amp;#34;myDataLake&amp;#34; sku DataLake.</description></item><item><title>The Farmer .NET Template</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/template/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:41:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/quickstarts/template/</guid><description>Farmer comes with a .NET template that makes getting started easy.
Creating a basic Farmer app The easiest way to create a Farmer app is to use the Farmer .NET Template.
dotnet new -i Farmer.Template dotnet new Farmer You only have to install the template once on your machine!
This creates a new dotnet application solution and project that looks by default as follows:
open Farmer open Farmer.Builders let deployment = arm { location Location.</description></item><item><title> Diagnostic Settings</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/diagnosticsetting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/diagnosticsetting/</guid><description>Overview The Diagnostic Settings builder is used to create diagnostic settings instances to send platform logs and metrics to different destinations (storage, event hub and log analytics). Support for Farmer builders and external resources is supported.
Diagnostic Settings (providers/diagnosticSettings) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Diagnostic Settings resource. metrics_source The resource that will be used for the source of logging and metrics information.</description></item><item><title>4. Providing Builder syntax</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/4-creating-builder-syntax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/4-creating-builder-syntax/</guid><description>If you want to get the nice json-like syntax for your configuration record, you need to implement a separate class which contains a set of methods that act on the Configuration Record that you created previously - one for each keyword that you want.
If you need have not built your own computation expression before, here are some background resources for you:
Office microsoft docs The &amp;ldquo;Computation Expressions&amp;rdquo; series Workshop Step 4.</description></item><item><title>Deploy an ASP.NET app</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/webapp-deploy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/webapp-deploy/</guid><description>Introduction This tutorial shows how to create the infrastructure required to host a ASP.NET web app, and how to automatically deploy that application with Farmer. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following steps:
Creating and configuring a basic ASP.NET web application. Creating a web app in Farmer. Deploying the web app through Farmer. Full code available here
Note: Your web application does can be a C# web application - it does not need to be written in F#!</description></item><item><title>Event Grid</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-grid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-grid/</guid><description>Overview The Event Grid is a simple but powerful builder that links events from Azure services such as Storage and App Service to one or many subscribers which can consume the events. The event grid builder supports a degree of type safety - all system events are provided from a strongly-typed list, and events are directly linked to specific builders - so, for example, you cannot accidentally subscribe to Storage Account events if the event publisher is a Web App.</description></item><item><title>ExpressRoute</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/express-route/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 21:57:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/express-route/</guid><description>Overview An ExpressRoute circuit is a dedicated link to Azure to provide communication with Azure services without traversing the Internet. It requires some coordination with a networking provider for these circuits, so some information, such as the service provider and peering location must be obtained from Azure reference documentation. The ExpressRoute builder creates an ExpressRoute circuit and enables Azure private peering and Microsoft peering.
ExpressRoute Namespace (Microsoft.Network/expressRouteCircuits) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose ExpressRoute service_provider Connectivity service provider from Azure reference documentation ExpressRoute peering_location Connectivity peering location from Azure reference documentation ExpressRoute tier Standard or Premium ExpressRoute family Metered or Unlimited data ExpressRoute bandwidth Bandwidth in Mbps for the circuit ExpressRoute add_peering Peering details for the circuit - can add Azure Private and Microsoft peerings Peering peering_type A network CIDR block of 4 IP addresses (/30) for the ExpressRoute primary circuit Peering peer_asn Peer Autonomous System Number - this is a uniquely assigned number for the peer network, typically provided by the service provider in agreement with Microsoft Peering azure_asn Azure Autonomous System Number - Microsoft oftent uses AS 12076 for Azure public, Azure private and Microsoft peering Peering primary_prefix A network CIDR block of 4 IP addresses (/30) for the ExpressRoute primary circuit Peering secondary_prefix A network CIDR block of 4 IP addresses (/30) for the ExpressRoute secondary circuit Peering vlan A unique VLAN ID for the peering Peering shared_key An optional shared key the service provider may specify for the peering Example open Farmer open Farmer.</description></item><item><title>Event Hub</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-hub/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-hub/</guid><description>Overview The Event Hub builder creates event hub namespaces, event hubs, consumer groups and authorization rules in a single builder.
Event Hub Namespace (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces) Event Hub (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces/eventhubs) Consumer Group (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces/eventhubs/consumergroups) Authorization Rule (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces/eventhubs/AuthorizationRules&amp;quot;) The Event Hub builder works in a similar fashion to the web app builder in that it automatically creates the host (in this case, the event hub namespace) when creating the event hub. If you wish to create multiple hubs in the same namespace, configure the namespace-level properties in the first event hub; subsequent event hubs should link to the namespace of the hub created by the first hub.</description></item><item><title>5. Unit Testing</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/5-unit-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/adding-resources/5-unit-testing/</guid><description>Usually I would be pro writing the tests before you implement all this but it is important to get a feel for the moving parts. At this point you may want to write some tests so you can iterate quickly on getting the structure of your ARM template correct.
The tests you will find in the project are black-box style tests that focus on the input of a resource and the output of the ARM template.</description></item><item><title>Creating Pull Requests</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/create-pull-requests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/create-pull-requests/</guid><description>This article is not a detailed guide on how to create a pull request (PR). See here to learn more about how to work with pull requests on GitHub.
The purpose of this article is to illustrate the main checklists you must go through before a PR will be considered for inclusion in Farmer. If you are new to Farmer, F# or GitHub - don&amp;rsquo;t worry. The team will be happy to support you getting your feature over the line.</description></item><item><title>Functions</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/functions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/functions/</guid><description>Overview The Functions builder is used to create Azure Functions accounts. It abstracts the App Host and Service Plan into the same component, and will also create and configure a linked App Insights resource. In addition, it will automatically create a backing storage account required by the functions runtime.
Web Site (Microsoft.Web/sites) Web Host (Microsoft.Web/serverfarms) Application Insights (Microsoft.Insights/components) Storage Accounts (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the functions instance.</description></item><item><title>IOT Hub</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/iot-hub/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:14:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/iot-hub/</guid><description>Overview The IOT Hub builder creates IOT Hub and linked Provision Services.
IOT Hubs (Microsoft.Devices/IotHubs) Provisioning Services (Microsoft.Devices/provisioningServices) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Specifies the name of the IOT Hub sku Sets the SKU of the IOT Hub capacity Sets the name of the capacity for the IOT Hub instance partition_count Sets the name of the SKU/Tier for the IOT Hub instance retention_days Sets the name of the SKU/Tier for the IOT Hub instance enable_device_provisioning Sets the name of the SKU/Tier for the IOT Hub instance Configuration Members Member Purpose GetKey Returns an ARM expression to retrieve the IOT Hub key for a specific policy e.</description></item><item><title>Key Vault</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/keyvault/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/keyvault/</guid><description>Overview The KeyVault package contains three builders, for the different components used by KeyVault: One for access policies, one for secrets, and one for the overall keyvault container.
KeyVault (Microsoft.KeyVault/vaults) Secrets (Microsoft.KeyVault/vaults/secrets) Secret Builder The secret builder allows you to store secrets into key vault. Values for a secret are passed by Secure String parameters.
Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the secret.</description></item><item><title>Log Analytics</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/loganalytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/loganalytics/</guid><description>Overview The Log Analytics builder is used to create Work space instances.
Log Analytics (Microsoft.OperationalInsights/workspaces) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the log analytics instance. retention_period Sets the retention period for logs in days. enable_ingestion Enables ingestion network traffic. enable_query Enables query network traffic. daily_cap Specifies an upper limit on the amount of data to ingest daily.</description></item><item><title>Managed Identity</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/managed-identity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 19:10:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/managed-identity/</guid><description>Overview Managed Identity is used to create an identity that resources can run under automatically. This is similar to a service principal except that there is no credential to manage and the authorization token is retrieved through a secure internal handshake between the resource and the identity service in Azure.
User Assigned Identity (Microsoft.ManagedIdentity/userAssignedIdentities) Using a managed identity as opposed to e.g. connection strings brings several benefits:
There is no client secret or certificate to configure and rotate because this is handled implicitly by Azure infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Maps</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/maps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 11:24:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/maps/</guid><description>Overview The Maps builder creates Azure Maps accounts.
Maps (Microsoft.Maps/accounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Azure Maps account. sku Sets the sku of the Azure Maps account. Example open Farmer open Farmer.Builders let myMaps = maps { name &amp;#34;mymaps&amp;#34; sku Maps.S0 }</description></item><item><title>Network Security Group</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/nsg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 16:44:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/nsg/</guid><description>Overview The Network Security Group builder creates network security groups with rules for securing network access to resources.
Network Security Groups (Microsoft.Network/networkSecurityGroups) Security Rules (Microsoft.Network/networkSecurityGroups/securityRules) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose nsg name Specifies the name of the network security group nsg add_rules Adds security rules to the network security group securityRule name The name of the security rule securityRule description The description of the security rule securityRule services The services port(s) and protocol(s) protected by this security rule securityRule add_source Specify access from any source protocol, address, and port securityRule add_source_any Specify access from any address and any port securityRule add_source_address Specify access from a specific address and any port securityRule add_source_network Specify access from a specific network and any port securityRule add_source_tag Specify access from a tagged source such as &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;VirtualNetwork&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;AzureLoadBalancer&amp;rdquo; securityRule add_destination Specify access to any source protocol, address, and port securityRule add_destination_any Specify access to any address and any port securityRule add_destination_address Specify access to a specific address and any port securityRule add_destination_network Specify access from a specific network and any port securityRule add_destination_tag Specify access to a tagged destination such as &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;VirtualNetwork&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;AzureLoadBalancer&amp;rdquo; securityRule allow Allows this traffic (the default) securityRule deny Denies this traffic Basic Example open Farmer open Farmer.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 07:14:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/postgresql/</guid><description>Overview The PostgreSQL module contains two builders - postgreSQL, used to create PostgreSQL Azure servers, and postgreSQLDb, used to create individual databases. It supports features such as firewall, autogrow and version selection. Every PostgreSQL Azure server you create will automatically create a SecureString parameter for the admin account password.
PostgreSQL server (Microsoft.DBforPostgreSQL/servers) PostgreSQL Builder keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose Server name (string) Sets the name of the PostgreSQL server.</description></item><item><title>Redis Cache</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/redis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/redis/</guid><description>Overview The Redis builder creates managed Redis Cache accounts.
Redis (Microsoft.Cache/redis) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Redis cache instance. sku Sets the sku of the Redis cache instance. capacity Sets the capacity level of the Redis cache instance, should be between 1-6 - see here. enable_non_ssl_port Enabled access to the cache over the non-SSL port.</description></item><item><title>SignalR</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/signalr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 11:13:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/signalr/</guid><description>Overview The SignalR builder creates SignalR services.
SignalR Service (Microsoft.SignalRService/signalR) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the SignalR service. sku Sets the sku of the SignalR service. capacity Sets the capacity of the SignalR service. (optional) allowed_origins Sets the allowed origins of the SignalR service. (optional) Configuration Members Member Purpose Key Returns an ARM expression to retrieve the primary connection string of the service.</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/search/</guid><description>Overview The Search builder creates storage accounts and their associated containers.
Search (Microsoft.Search/searchServices) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Azure Search instance. sku Sets the sku of the Azure Search instance. replicas Sets the replica count of the Azure Search instance. partitions Sets the number of partitions of the Azure Search instance.</description></item><item><title>Service Bus</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/service-bus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/service-bus/</guid><description>Overview The Service Bus builder creates service bus namespaces and their associated queues.
Service Bus Namespaces (Microsoft.ServiceBus/namespaces) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose Queue name The name of the queue. Queue lock_duration_minutes The length of time that a lock can be held on a message. Queue max_delivery_count The maximum number of times a message can be delivered before dead lettering.</description></item><item><title>SQL Azure</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/sql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/sql/</guid><description>Overview The SQL Azure module contains two builders - sqlServer, used to create SQL Azure servers, and sqlDb, used to create individual databases. It supports features such as encryption, firewalls and automatic pool creation. Every SQL Azure server you create will automatically create a SecureString parameter for the admin account password.
SQL Azure server (Microsoft.Sql/servers) SQL Server Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose server_name Sets the name of the SQL server.</description></item><item><title>Static Web Apps</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/static-web-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/static-web-app/</guid><description>Overview The Static Web App builder is used to create Static Web Apps. The Static Web App service is modern web app service that offers streamlined full-stack development from source code to global high availability. You can use it to host static web applications and Azure Functions in a single resource, using GitHub native workflows to build and deploy your application.
Static Site (Microsoft.Web/staticSites) At the time of writing, Static Web Apps are in public preview.</description></item><item><title>Storage Account</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/storage-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/storage-account/</guid><description>Overview The Storage Account builder creates storage accounts and their associated containers.
Storage Accounts (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts) Storage Containers (blobServices/containers) File Shares (fileServices/shares) Queues (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts/queueServices/queues) Tables (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts/tableServices/tables) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Specifies the name of the storage account sku Sets the SKU of the storage account. A set of predefined SKU values are available as members in Storage.Sku, but you can create the full range of combinations of Kind and SKU as needed.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/vnet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 11:22:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/vnet/</guid><description>Overview The Virtual Network builder (vnet) is used to create Azure Virtual Network instances.
Virtual Network (Microsoft.Network/virtualNetworks) Subnets (Microsoft.Network/virtualNetworks/subnets) Builder Keywords Resource Keyword Purpose vnet name Sets the name of the virtual network. vnet add_address_spaces Adds address spaces to the virtual network. vnet add_subnets Adds subnets to the virtual network. vnet build_address_spaces Automatically builds address spaces for subnet names and sizes.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network Gateway</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/vnet-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 10:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/vnet-gateway/</guid><description>Overview The Virtual Network Gateway builder creates virtual network gateways for ExpressRoute or VPN connections to a virtual network.
Virtual Network Gateways (Microsoft.Network/virtualNetworkGatways) Connections (Microsoft.Network/connections) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose Gateway name Specifies the name of the virtual network gateway Gateway vnet The name of the virtual network to which the gateway connects Gateway er_gateway_sku SKU for an ExpressRoute gateway Gateway vpn_gateway_sku SKU for a VPN gateway Gateway vpn_type Sets the VPN type to route-based (default) or policy-based.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Machine</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/virtual-machine/</guid><description>Overview The Virtual Machine builder creates a fully configured virtual machine and all its required child resources.
Virtual Machines (Microsoft.Compute/virtualMachines) Virtual Networks (Microsoft.Network/virtualNetworks) IP Addresses (Microsoft.Network/publicIPAddresses) Network Interfaces (Microsoft.Network/networkInterfaces) Storage Accounts (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts) In addition, every VM you create will add a SecureString parameter to the ARM template, whose name follows the pattern password-for-[virtual machine name].
Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the VM.</description></item><item><title>Web App</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/web-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/web-app/</guid><description>Overview The Web App builder is used to create Azure App Service accounts. It abstracts the Service Plan into the same component, and will also create and configure a linked App Insights resource. If you wish to create a website that connects to an existing service plan, use the link_to_service_plan keyword and provide the resource name of the service plan to connect to.
Web Site (Microsoft.Web/sites) Server Farms (Microsoft.Web/serverfarms) Source Controls (Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Declarative Steps in an ARM Deployment</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/keyvault-certs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/keyvault-certs/</guid><description>Introduction An ARM deployment typically represents the infrastructure you want deployed as a result of it, referred to as the &amp;ldquo;goal state&amp;rdquo;. For instance, you may want to have a web application with a database, so you&amp;rsquo;ll define your goal state that includes database and web application resources. However, it&amp;rsquo;s not always that simple - there are various reasons that some of the steps of a deployment cannot be represented by the goal state resource model.</description></item><item><title>Create your own Minecraft Server</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/minecraft-server-aci/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/minecraft-server-aci/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;ll use dotnet framework features and F# language techniques when building a template to create a fully functional Minecraft Server running on an Azure Container Instance with its world data stored in an Azure Storage Account. Because Farmer is a domain specific language embedded within F#, you are able to utilize the rich dotnet ecosystem and a static type system to &amp;ldquo;craft&amp;rdquo; an advanced deployment.
Programmatically build our Minecraft configuration files.</description></item><item><title>F# Script in a Container Group</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/aci-fsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/aci-fsx/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial, you will deploy an F# script directly to an Azure Container Group. This is useful when you need to fill a gap in your solution with some quick application logic or to test scenarios on Azure before building a more complex application. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following steps:
Create a brief F# script. Create a container instance. Include the script on a volume that will be attached to the container when started.</description></item><item><title>Cosmos-backed Web App</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/cosmos-backed-webapp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/cosmos-backed-webapp/</guid><description>Introduction This tutorial walks you through creating a web application which is backed by a Cosmos DB database, and is fully configured with connection string settings for you to start developing against. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following steps:
Creating a Cosmos DB account with a single database. Creating a web application with an automatically configured app insights instance. Configuring the web application to have the connection settings required to connect to the Cosmos DB instance.</description></item><item><title>Multiple web apps</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/multiple-web-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/multiple-web-apps/</guid><description>Introduction This tutorial walks you through creating multiple web applications that will share a common web server. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following steps:
Creating a web app. Creating multiple web apps and &amp;ldquo;sharing&amp;rdquo; the first web app&amp;rsquo;s service plan and Application Insights instances. How to use F#&amp;lsquo;s list comprehensions to rapidly creating multiple websites. Full code available here
Creating a single web app Create a standard web app as normal:</description></item><item><title>Serverless ETL</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/serverless-etl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/serverless-etl/</guid><description>Introduction This tutorial shows how to create the infrastructure required to implement a common pattern for code-first &amp;ldquo;extract-transform-load&amp;rdquo; (ETL) processes. In this tutorial, imagine you wish to react to data being created in a blob in Storage, then parse it, and finally insert the &amp;ldquo;parsed&amp;rdquo; data into SQL in a relational database for use by e.g. a web application. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following steps:
Creating an Azure Functions instance, with automatically configured storage and app insights instances.</description></item><item><title>Web App Secrets with KeyVault</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/web-storage-keyvault/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/tutorials/web-storage-keyvault/</guid><description>Introduction This tutorial shows how to create the infrastructure required to host a web app which can retrieve secrets from a secure store (Keyvault) using Azure identity. In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll store the key for a storage account in Keyvault, but it could be anything. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the following steps:
Creating a Web App, Storage Account and a KeyVault instance. Safely adding the Storage Account key into KeyVault. Granting a read-only trust between KeyVault and the Web App.</description></item></channel></rss>