<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Farmer</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Farmer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 22:37:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AKS Cluster</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/aks-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 19:30:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/aks-cluster/</guid><description>Overview The AKS Cluster builder is used to create AKS clusters.
Container Group (Microsoft.ContainerService/managedClusters) AKS Builder Keywords The AKS Builder constructs AKS clusters.
Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the AKS cluster. dns_prefix Sets the DNS prefix of the AKS cluster. enable_rbac Enable Kubernetes Role-Based Access Control. add_agent_pools Adds agent pools to the AKS cluster.</description></item><item><title>App Insights</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/app-insights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/app-insights/</guid><description>Overview The App Insights builder is used to create Application Insights accounts. Use this if you need a standalone AI instance; if you need one for a web app, the web app will create one by default and configure the application settings automatically.
Application Insights (Microsoft.Insights/components) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the App Insights instance. disable_ip_masking Disable IP masking.</description></item><item><title>ARM Deployment</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/arm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/arm/</guid><description>Overview The ARM deployment builder is always the top-level element of your deployment. It contains the manifest of all Farmer resources that you create.
Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose location Sets the default location of all resources. add_resource Adds a resource to the template. add_resources Adds a collection of resources to the template. output Creates an output value that will be returned by the ARM template.</description></item><item><title>Bastion Host</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/bastion-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/bastion-host/</guid><description>Overview The Bastion Host builder creates a bastion host to access resources inside a virtual network. It also creates a static public IP for the bastion host.
BastionHosts (Microsoft.Network/bastionHosts) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose BastionHost vnet Name of the virtual network the bastion host can access Example #r @&amp;#34;./libs/Newtonsoft.Json.dll&amp;#34; #r @&amp;#34;../../src/Farmer/bin/Debug/netstandard2.0/Farmer.dll&amp;#34; open Farmer open Farmer.Builders arm { location Location.</description></item><item><title>CDN</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cdn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cdn/</guid><description>Overview The CDN builder is used to create Azure Content Delivery Network instances.
CDN Profile (Microsoft.Cdn/profiles) CDN Endpoint (Microsoft.Cdn/profiles/endpoints) CDN Custom Domain (Microsoft.Cdn/profiles/endpoints/customDomains) There are two builders available:
The CDN builder, which maps to a CDN profile. The Endpoint builder, which creates endpoints and custom domains. Endpoints are created within a CDN. CDN Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the CDN instance.</description></item><item><title>Cognitive Services</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cognitive-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cognitive-services/</guid><description>Overview The Cognitive Services builder is used to create Azure Cognitive Services instances.
Cognitive Services (Microsoft.CognitiveServices/accounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Cognitive Services instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to F0 (free). api Specifies the Kind of api to use for the service instance. Defaults to AllInOne. Configuration Members Member Purpose Key Gets the ARM expression path to the Key of this Cognitive Services instance.</description></item><item><title>Deployment Script</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/deployment-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 15:19:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/deployment-script/</guid><description>Overview The Deployment Script builder is used to execute Azure CLI scripts as part of an ARM deployment.
Deployment Script (Microsoft.Resources/deploymentScripts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the deployment script resource. arguments List of arguments to pass to the script. cli Specifies the CLI runtime, default is az cli. content Sets script content for the resource.</description></item><item><title>Container Group</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 19:30:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-group/</guid><description>Overview The Container Group builder is used to create Azure Container Group instances.
Container Group (Microsoft.ContainerInstance/containerGroups) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose containerInstance name Sets the name of the Container Group instance. containerInstance image Sets the container image. containerInstance command Sets the commands to execute within the container instance in exec form. containerInstance add_ports Sets the ports the container exposes.</description></item><item><title>Container Registry</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-registry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 19:10:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/container-registry/</guid><description>Overview The Container Registry builder is used to create Azure Container Registry (ACR) instances.
Container Registry (Microsoft.ContainerRegistry/registries) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Container Registry instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to Basic. enable_admin_user The value that indicates whether the admin user is enabled. Example open Farmer open Farmer.</description></item><item><title>Cosmos DB</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cosmos-db/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/cosmos-db/</guid><description>Overview The CosmosDb package containers two builders, used to create databases and containers.
CosmosDB Account (Microsoft.DocumentDb/databaseAccounts) CosmosDB SQL (&amp;quot;Microsoft.DocumentDB/databaseAccounts/sqlDatabases) CosmosDB SQL Container (Microsoft.DocumentDb/databaseAccounts/sqlDatabases/containers) There is currently only support for document databases (the so-called &amp;ldquo;SQL API&amp;rdquo;), with support for Gremlin, Table and Cassandra data models planned.
Cosmos DB Builder The CosmosDB builder abstracts the idea of account and database into one. If you wish to &amp;ldquo;re-use&amp;rdquo; an already-created Cosmos DB account, use link_to_account keyword - no account will be created and the database will be attached to the existing one.</description></item><item><title>DNS Zone</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 18:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/dns/</guid><description>Overview The DNS Zone module contains two types of builders - dnsZone, used to create DNS Zones, and ___Record (like cnameRecord, aRecord, ..), used to create DNS Records sets. It supports most record types (except SOA, SRV and CAA) and has specific builders for every record type.
DNS Zone (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones) A Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/A) AAAA Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/AAAA) CNAME Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/CNAME) TXT Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/TXT) MX Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/MX) NS Record (Microsoft.Network/dnsZones/NS) PTR Record (Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Data Lake</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/data-lake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:55:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/data-lake/</guid><description>Overview The Data Lake builder is used to create Azure Data Lake instances.
Data Lake (Microsoft.DataLakeStore/accounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Cognitive Services instance. sku Sets the SKU of the instance. Defaults to Consumption. enable_encryption Turns on data lake encryption. Example open Farmer open Farmer.Builders let myLake = dataLake { name &amp;#34;myDataLake&amp;#34; sku DataLake.</description></item><item><title>Event Grid</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-grid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-grid/</guid><description>Overview The Event Grid is a simple but powerful builder that links events from Azure services such as Storage and App Service to one or many subscribers which can consume the events. The event grid builder supports a degree of type safety - all system events are provided from a strongly-typed list, and events are directly linked to specific builders - so, for example, you cannot accidentally subscribe to Storage Account events if the event publisher is a Web App.</description></item><item><title>Event Hub</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-hub/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/event-hub/</guid><description>Overview The Event Hub builder creates event hub namespaces, event hubs, consumer groups and authorization rules in a single builder.
Event Hub Namespace (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces) Event Hub (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces/eventhubs) Consumer Group (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces/eventhubs/consumergroups) Authorization Rule (Microsoft.EventHub/namespaces/eventhubs/AuthorizationRules&amp;quot;) The Event Hub builder works in a similar fashion to the web app builder in that it automatically creates the host (in this case, the event hub namespace) when creating the event hub. If you wish to create multiple hubs in the same namespace, configure the namespace-level properties in the first event hub; subsequent event hubs should link to the namespace of the hub created by the first hub.</description></item><item><title>ExpressRoute</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/express-route/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 21:57:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/express-route/</guid><description>Overview An ExpressRoute circuit is a dedicated link to Azure to provide communication with Azure services without traversing the Internet. It requires some coordination with a networking provider for these circuits, so some information, such as the service provider and peering location must be obtained from Azure reference documentation. The ExpressRoute builder creates an ExpressRoute circuit and enables Azure private peering and Microsoft peering.
ExpressRoute Namespace (Microsoft.Network/expressRouteCircuits) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose ExpressRoute service_provider Connectivity service provider from Azure reference documentation ExpressRoute peering_location Connectivity peering location from Azure reference documentation ExpressRoute tier Standard or Premium ExpressRoute family Metered or Unlimited data ExpressRoute bandwidth Bandwidth in Mbps for the circuit ExpressRoute add_peering Peering details for the circuit - can add Azure Private and Microsoft peerings Peering peering_type A network CIDR block of 4 IP addresses (/30) for the ExpressRoute primary circuit Peering peer_asn Peer Autonomous System Number - this is a uniquely assigned number for the peer network, typically provided by the service provider in agreement with Microsoft Peering azure_asn Azure Autonomous System Number - Microsoft oftent uses AS 12076 for Azure public, Azure private and Microsoft peering Peering primary_prefix A network CIDR block of 4 IP addresses (/30) for the ExpressRoute primary circuit Peering secondary_prefix A network CIDR block of 4 IP addresses (/30) for the ExpressRoute secondary circuit Peering vlan A unique VLAN ID for the peering Peering shared_key An optional shared key the service provider may specify for the peering Example open Farmer open Farmer.</description></item><item><title>Functions</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/functions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/functions/</guid><description>Overview The Functions builder is used to create Azure Functions accounts. It abstracts the App Host and Service Plan into the same component, and will also create and configure a linked App Insights resource. In addition, it will automatically create a backing storage account required by the functions runtime.
Web Site (Microsoft.Web/sites) Web Host (Microsoft.Web/serverfarms) Application Insights (Microsoft.Insights/components) Storage Accounts (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the functions instance.</description></item><item><title>IOT Hub</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/iot-hub/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:14:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/iot-hub/</guid><description>Overview The IOT Hub builder creates IOT Hub and linked Provision Services.
IOT Hubs (Microsoft.Devices/IotHubs) Provisioning Services (Microsoft.Devices/provisioningServices) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Specifies the name of the IOT Hub sku Sets the SKU of the IOT Hub capacity Sets the name of the capacity for the IOT Hub instance partition_count Sets the name of the SKU/Tier for the IOT Hub instance retention_days Sets the name of the SKU/Tier for the IOT Hub instance enable_device_provisioning Sets the name of the SKU/Tier for the IOT Hub instance Configuration Members Member Purpose GetKey Returns an ARM expression to retrieve the IOT Hub key for a specific policy e.</description></item><item><title>Key Vault</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/keyvault/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/keyvault/</guid><description>Overview The KeyVault package contains three builders, for the different components used by KeyVault: One for access policies, one for secrets, and one for the overall keyvault container.
KeyVault (Microsoft.KeyVault/vaults) Secrets (Microsoft.KeyVault/vaults/secrets) Secret Builder The secret builder allows you to store secrets into key vault. Values for a secret are passed by Secure String parameters.
Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the secret.</description></item><item><title>Log Analytics</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/loganalytics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/loganalytics/</guid><description>Overview The Log Analytics builder is used to create Work space instances.
Log Analytics (Microsoft.OperationalInsights/workspaces) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the log analytics instance. retention_period Sets the retention period for logs in days. enable_ingestion Enables ingestion network traffic. enable_query Enables query network traffic. daily_cap Specifies an upper limit on the amount of data to ingest daily.</description></item><item><title>Managed Identity</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/managed-identity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 19:10:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/managed-identity/</guid><description>Overview Managed Identity is used to create an identity that resources can run under automatically. This is similar to a service principal except that there is no credential to manage and the authorization token is retrieved through a secure internal handshake between the resource and the identity service in Azure.
User Assigned Identity (Microsoft.ManagedIdentity/userAssignedIdentities) Using a managed identity as opposed to e.g. connection strings brings several benefits:
There is no client secret or certificate to configure and rotate because this is handled implicitly by Azure infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Maps</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/maps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 11:24:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/maps/</guid><description>Overview The Maps builder creates Azure Maps accounts.
Maps (Microsoft.Maps/accounts) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Azure Maps account. sku Sets the sku of the Azure Maps account. Example open Farmer open Farmer.Builders let myMaps = maps { name &amp;#34;mymaps&amp;#34; sku Maps.S0 }</description></item><item><title>Network Security Group</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/nsg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 16:44:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/nsg/</guid><description>Overview The Network Security Group builder creates network security groups with rules for securing network access to resources.
Network Security Groups (Microsoft.Network/networkSecurityGroups) Security Rules (Microsoft.Network/networkSecurityGroups/securityRules) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose nsg name Specifies the name of the network security group nsg add_rules Adds security rules to the network security group securityRule name The name of the security rule securityRule description The description of the security rule securityRule services The services port(s) and protocol(s) protected by this security rule securityRule add_source Specify access from any source protocol, address, and port securityRule add_source_any Specify access from any address and any port securityRule add_source_address Specify access from a specific address and any port securityRule add_source_network Specify access from a specific network and any port securityRule add_source_tag Specify access from a tagged source such as &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;VirtualNetwork&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;AzureLoadBalancer&amp;rdquo; securityRule add_destination Specify access to any source protocol, address, and port securityRule add_destination_any Specify access to any address and any port securityRule add_destination_address Specify access to a specific address and any port securityRule add_destination_network Specify access from a specific network and any port securityRule add_destination_tag Specify access to a tagged destination such as &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;VirtualNetwork&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;AzureLoadBalancer&amp;rdquo; securityRule allow Allows this traffic (the default) securityRule deny Denies this traffic Basic Example open Farmer open Farmer.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 07:14:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/postgresql/</guid><description>Overview The PostgreSQL module contains two builders - postgreSQL, used to create PostgreSQL Azure servers, and postgreSQLDb, used to create individual databases. It supports features such as firewall, autogrow and version selection. Every PostgreSQL Azure server you create will automatically create a SecureString parameter for the admin account password.
PostgreSQL server (Microsoft.DBforPostgreSQL/servers) PostgreSQL Builder keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose Server name (string) Sets the name of the PostgreSQL server.</description></item><item><title>Redis Cache</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/redis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/redis/</guid><description>Overview The Redis builder creates managed Redis Cache accounts.
Redis (Microsoft.Cache/redis) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Redis cache instance. sku Sets the sku of the Redis cache instance. capacity Sets the capacity level of the Redis cache instance, should be between 1-6 - see here. enable_non_ssl_port Enabled access to the cache over the non-SSL port.</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/search/</guid><description>Overview The Search builder creates storage accounts and their associated containers.
Search (Microsoft.Search/searchServices) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the Azure Search instance. sku Sets the sku of the Azure Search instance. replicas Sets the replica count of the Azure Search instance. partitions Sets the number of partitions of the Azure Search instance.</description></item><item><title>Service Bus</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/service-bus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/service-bus/</guid><description>Overview The Service Bus builder creates service bus namespaces and their associated queues.
Service Bus Namespaces (Microsoft.ServiceBus/namespaces) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose Queue name The name of the queue. Queue lock_duration_minutes The length of time that a lock can be held on a message. Queue max_delivery_count The maximum number of times a message can be delivered before dead lettering.</description></item><item><title>SignalR</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/signalr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 11:13:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/signalr/</guid><description>Overview The SignalR builder creates SignalR services.
SignalR Service (Microsoft.SignalRService/signalR) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the SignalR service. sku Sets the sku of the SignalR service. capacity Sets the capacity of the SignalR service. (optional) allowed_origins Sets the allowed origins of the SignalR service. (optional) Configuration Members Member Purpose Key Returns an ARM expression to retrieve the primary connection string of the service.</description></item><item><title>Static Web Apps</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/static-web-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/static-web-app/</guid><description>Overview The Static Web App builder is used to create Static Web Apps. The Static Web App service is modern web app service that offers streamlined full-stack development from source code to global high availability. You can use it to host static web applications and Azure Functions in a single resource, using GitHub native workflows to build and deploy your application.
Static Site (Microsoft.Web/staticSites) At the time of writing, Static Web Apps are in public preview.</description></item><item><title>Storage Account</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/storage-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/storage-account/</guid><description>Overview The Storage Account builder creates storage accounts and their associated containers.
Storage Accounts (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts) Storage Containers (blobServices/containers) File Shares (fileServices/shares) Queues (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts/queueServices/queues) Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Specifies the name of the storage account sku Sets the SKU of the storage account. A set of predefined SKU values are available as members in Storage.Sku, but you can create the full range of combinations of Kind and SKU as needed.</description></item><item><title>SQL Azure</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/sql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/sql/</guid><description>Overview The SQL Azure module contains two builders - sqlServer, used to create SQL Azure servers, and sqlDb, used to create individual databases. It supports features such as encryption, firewalls and automatic pool creation. Every SQL Azure server you create will automatically create a SecureString parameter for the admin account password.
SQL Azure server (Microsoft.Sql/servers) SQL Server Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose server_name Sets the name of the SQL server.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Machine</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/virtual-machine/</guid><description>Overview The Virtual Machine builder creates a fully configured virtual machine and all its required child resources.
Virtual Machines (Microsoft.Compute/virtualMachines) Virtual Networks (Microsoft.Network/virtualNetworks) IP Addresses (Microsoft.Network/publicIPAddresses) Network Interfaces (Microsoft.Network/networkInterfaces) Storage Accounts (Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts) In addition, every VM you create will add a SecureString parameter to the ARM template, whose name follows the pattern password-for-[virtual machine name].
Builder Keywords Keyword Purpose name Sets the name of the VM.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Network Gateway</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/vnet-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 10:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/vnet-gateway/</guid><description>Overview The Virtual Network Gateway builder creates virtual network gateways for ExpressRoute or VPN connections to a virtual network.
Virtual Network Gateways (Microsoft.Network/virtualNetworkGatways) Connections (Microsoft.Network/connections) Builder Keywords Applies To Keyword Purpose Gateway name Specifies the name of the virtual network gateway Gateway vnet The name of the virtual network to which the gateway connects Gateway er_gateway_sku SKU for an ExpressRoute gateway Gateway vpn_gateway_sku SKU for a VPN gateway Gateway vpn_type Sets the VPN type to route-based (default) or policy-based.</description></item><item><title>Web App</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/web-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:53:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/api-overview/resources/web-app/</guid><description>Overview The Web App builder is used to create Azure App Service accounts. It abstracts the Service Plan into the same component, and will also create and configure a linked App Insights resource. If you wish to create a website that connects to an existing service plan, use the link_to_service_plan keyword and provide the resource name of the service plan to connect to.
Web Site (Microsoft.Web/sites) Server Farms (Microsoft.Web/serverfarms) Source Controls (Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>