<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributing on Farmer</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/</link><description>Recent content in Contributing on Farmer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 03:57:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ARM Basics</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/arm-basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/arm-basics/</guid><description>Skip this section if you are already familiar with ARM Templates
This won&amp;rsquo;t be an introduction to Azure Resource Manager or ARM templates. Instead let&amp;rsquo;s go through the main parts that are important for creating a new resource.
The main parts of ARM Templates can be broken into resources, outputs, variables, and parameters. Farmer has limited support for parameters and no support for variables, so we will not cover them.</description></item><item><title>Outputs and ARM Expressions</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/outputs-and-expressions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:50:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/outputs-and-expressions/</guid><description>Outputs can be created in Farmer for any ARM Expression, Resource Name or any optional string. ARM Expressions are most useful in this case for referring to values that only exist at deployment time, such as connection strings.
Creating ARM Expressions Farmer ARM expressions are in reality just wrapped strings, and are easy to create. For example, the code to create a Storage Key property is similar to this:</description></item><item><title>Creating Pull Requests</title><link>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/create-pull-requests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://compositionalit.github.io/farmer/contributing/create-pull-requests/</guid><description>This article is not a detailed guide on how to create a pull request (PR). See here to learn more about how to work with pull requests on GitHub.
The purpose of this article is to illustrate the main checklists you must go through before a PR will be considered for inclusion in Farmer. If you are new to Farmer, F# or GitHub - don&amp;rsquo;t worry. The team will be happy to support you getting your feature over the line.</description></item></channel></rss>